Guide to the Piet Mondrian Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Other Papers, 1881-1944; Series II; 1.04; (3 boxes)
  - Personal Papers
    - Declaration of Intention for United States citizenship, 1941 Sep 22 (Box 4, Folder 106)
    - Museum of Modern Art admissions pass, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 107)
    - Last will and testament (typescript carbon and photocopy), 1942 Apr 16 (Box 4, Folder 108)
    - Exhibition announcement, Valentine Gallery, 1943 Mar-Apr (Box 4, Folder 109)
    - Autograph letter, signed, from Agathe Zethraeus, Stockholm, 1943 Nov 9 (Box 4, Folder 110)
    - Lease for studio at 15 East 59th Street, New York, 1943 Jul 26 (Box 4, Folder 111)
    - United States War Ration Books (2), 1943 (Box 4, Folder 112)
    - Autograph letter, signed, from Stuart Davis to Harry Holtzman, 1944 Feb 2 (Box 4, Folder 113)
    - Lease termination agreement, 15 East 59th Street, 1944 May 31 (Box 4, Folder 114)
    - Autograph letter (or essay?), signed, from T. B. (possibly Til Brugman), undated (Box 4, Folder 115)
    - Empty envelopes, undated (Box 4, Folder 116)
    - Drawing by Mondrian, undated
  - Publications
    Includes several issues of De Stijl most likely collected by Harry Holtzman.
    - Alcyone, Aan de voeten van den Meester (Amsterdam: Theosofische Uitgevers-Maatschappij, 1913) (Box 5, Folder 117)
    - L'Anglais Appris en Quelques Jours (London: Hugo's Institute for Teaching Foreign Languages, 1914); 2 vol. (Box 5, Folder 118)
    - Bendien, J., "Piet Mondriaan--60 Jaar," in Elsevier's Geïllustreerd Maandschrift, vol. 42, no. 84 (1932): p. 168-174 (offprint) (Box 5, Folder 119)
    - Bill, Max, "Aan Piet Mondriaan op zijn 70en Verjaardag," in De 8 en Opbouw, vol. 13, no. 12, December 1942 (Box 5, Folder 120)
    - Catalogue of the International Exhibition of Modern Art assembled by the Société Anonyme (New York: Anderson Galleries, 1927) (Box 5, Folder 121)
    - Collins, Mabel, Licht op het Pad en Karma (Amsterdam: Uitgave van de N. V. Theosof. Uitg.-Maatschappij, 1919), 1918 (Box 5, Folder 122)
    - Domselaer, Jakob van, Proeve van Stijlkunst No. 8 (musical score); attachment to Het Journaal van den Nieuwen Kring, vol. 1, no. 14, 1916 (Box 5, Folder 123)
    - Everybody's French Dictionary: French-English, English-French (London: W. Foulsham & Co. Ltd., 1926) (Box 5, Folder 124)
    - Hay, William Howard, The Medical Millennium (Pittsburgh: Pittsburgh Health Club, 1927) (Box 5, Folder 125-126)
      Autograph inscription to Mondrian from Jeanne Hélion; accompanied by six pages of Mondrian's autograph notes on diet, a newspaper clipping, and two pieces of printed advertising ephemera.
    - Janis, Sidney, "School of Paris Comes to U.S.," in Decision, vol. 2, no. 5-6 (November-December 1941): 85-93 (2 copies) (Box 5, Folder 127)
    - Marinetti, F. T. Les Mots en Liberté Futuristes (Milan: Edizioni futuriste di "Poesia," 1919) (Box 5, Folder 128)
      Autograph inscription to Mondrian by the author.
    - A New Pocket-Dictionary of the English and Dutch Languages (Tiel: H.C.A. Campagne & Zoon), 3rd revised edition, undated (Box 5, Folder 129)
    - Steiner, Rudolph, Verslag van de Voordrachten (Amsterdam: Theosofische Uitgevers-Maatschappij, 1908) (Box 6, Folder 130)
    - De Stijl, vol. 1, no 1, 2, 4, 5, and three detached pages, 1917-1918 (Box 6, Folder 131)
    - De Stijl, vol. 1, no. 6, 7, 8, 9, 10, 12, 1918 (Box 6, Folder 132)
    - De Stijl, vol. 3, no. 2, 3, 4, 7, 8, 10, 11, 1920 (Box 6, Folder 133)
    - De Stijl NB, no. 3/4, 6/7, 9, 73/74, 77, 78, 1923-1927 (Box 6, Folder 134)
    - Suarès, Carlo, Krishnamurti (Paris: Editions Adyar, 1933) (Box 6, Folder 135)
    - Sur le Seuil, Traduit de l'Anglais par P. E. B. (Paris: Publications Théosophiques, 1928) (Box 6, Folder 136)
    - Sweeney, James Johnson, "An Interview with Mondrian," in Bulletin of Modern Art, vol. 12, no. 4 & 5 (1946), p. 15-16 (photocopy), undated (Box 6, Folder 137)
- Oversize, 9
  - Detached leaves from Vouloir (March 1926) (in Series I) (Box 7 (Oversize), Folder 138)
  - Detached leaves from Cahiers d'Art, vol. 1, no. 7 (1926) (in Series I) (Box 7 (Oversize), Folder 139)
  - Clipping from Neue Zürcher Zeitung, no. 2060 (October 26, 1929) (in Series I) (Box 7 (Oversize), Folder 140)
  - Detached leaves from Cercle et Carré, no. 2 (April 15, 1930) (in Series I) (Box 7 (Oversize), Folder 141)
  - Detached leaves from Cahiers d'Art, vol. 6 (1931) (in Series I) (Box 7 (Oversize), Folder 142)
  - Detached leaves from Cahiers d'Art, vol. 10, no. 1-4 (1935) (in Series I) (Box 7 (Oversize), Folder 143)
  - Diploma for Secondary School Art Teaching (in Series II), 1892 Sep 10 (Box 7 (Oversize), Folder 144)
  - Drawing by Mondrian (in Series II), undated (Box 7 (Oversize), Folder 145)
  - Newspaper clippings about Mondrian (in Series II), 1926-1942 (Box 8 (Oversize), Folder 146)